<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oscar D&#39;amico</title>
    <link>https://odamico.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Oscar D&#39;amico</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://odamico.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ARP poisoning using Kali Linux</title>
      <link>https://odamico.github.io/posts/arppoisoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odamico.github.io/posts/arppoisoning/</guid>
      <description>One of the fundamental protocols in the TCP/IP stack is the address resolution protocol, or ARP for short. This protocol maps IPv4 addresses to MAC addresses but performs no authentication by design. Because of this, we can send our own ARP traffic onto the network claiming to own an IP address which we really don&#39;t. In this post, I will be using this to my advantage in an ARP spoofing attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Project: Creating a Command Line Pokedex in Python3</title>
      <link>https://odamico.github.io/posts/minidex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odamico.github.io/posts/minidex/</guid>
      <description>Solving interesting problems and creating neat applications have always been the best motivators for me to program. While playing Pokemon Sun, I found myself googling the new species I would encounter quite often. I would take time to look at their stats and what they were weak to and strong against. These searches started taking up time very quickly. For reference, each page contains a table of contents like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://odamico.github.io/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odamico.github.io/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I am currently pursuing an Honours Bachelor of Technology degree in Informatics and Security at Seneca College. My tech journey began with Java programming for my highschool computer science classes. From there, I learned about computer hardware basics through private classes. So far studying at Seneca, I have learned networking, Linux system administration, C programming, computer forensics, reverse engineering, database administration, penetration testing, and so much more. In my free time I enjoy practicing these skills and tinkering around with my own personal tech projects, this blog is dedicated to demonstrating some of those projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post Using Hugo and Github Pages</title>
      <link>https://odamico.github.io/posts/post-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://odamico.github.io/posts/post-title/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! Welcome to my new GitHub Pages blog This site was generated using Hugo, a fast and simple framework for building static webpages. Hugo works nicely with GitHub pages for hosting simple web content. I hope to post personal projects and guides related to information security, programming, game development, data science, and more!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>